[{"id": "5989ae8fcb8751d53e7d7616", "question": "What was the first commercially successful method of manufacturing artificial gemstones?", "answer": "The Verneuil Process (also known as flame fusion)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05f", "question": "What famous Cherokee Indian created the alphabet for the Cherokee language?", "answer": "Sequoyah", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c7ad877e98cb977789d5", "question": "What is the only country to lie entirely in the Alpine region?", "answer": "Lichtenstein", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133916f", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2cf", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The Red Baron\"?", "answer": "Manfred von Richtofen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ce", "question": "Which one of your toes is also known as your \"hallux\"?", "answer": "Big toe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4b4549076251badbeac1", "question": "Who was the first female U.S. Attorney General?", "answer": "Janet Reno -- She served as the attorney general for President Bill Clinton's entire presidency.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3c5", "question": "Which city is known as the Windy City?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339049", "question": "Who composed \"The Dream of Gerontius\"?", "answer": "Edward Elgar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbe", "question": "\"One Giant Leap\" was the first biography ever written of whom?", "answer": "Neil Armstrong", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c39", "question": "What book won Harper Lee a Pulitzer Prize in 1961?", "answer": "To Kill A Mockingbird", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339216", "question": "What fictional Kansas town is the earthly home of the young Superman?", "answer": "Smallville", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc1ed6ce05a3942286f18", "question": "What country is the setting for the film \"The Deep\"?", "answer": "Bermuda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aace", "question": "What is the capital of Brazil?", "answer": "Brasilia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff14040b0ee8c595b6d3998", "question": "What melting food provided the inspiration for Dali's melting clocks?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f6a", "question": "Who replaces Professor Snape as Potions Master at Hogwarts?", "answer": "Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ef0e08d98002fdd633dd", "question": "What is the fear of numbers known as?", "answer": "Numerophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f6", "question": "What is the correct term for a group of whales?", "answer": "Pod", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d2", "question": "How does James Bond like his martinis?", "answer": "Shaken", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b2b401dd7bf43be5e7a1", "question": "A \"smack\" is a group of what?", "answer": "Jellyfish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e9b", "question": "What movie did the villain Harry Powell appear in?", "answer": "The Night of the Hunter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9dfcfe748bb36357acdea", "question": "What Norman Rockwell painting is based on a clash between civil rights workers and the Ku Klux Klan?", "answer": "Southern Justice (Murder in Mississippi)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb582f5dad637d903c880f", "question": "What animal is considered to be symbolic of Venice?", "answer": "Lion -- The Lion of St. Mark is a symbol that appears throughout the city.  It honors St. Mark, who is the patron saint of Venice.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5df", "question": "What was ornithologist Robert Stroud's nickname?", "answer": "The Birdman of Alcatraz", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa6196ce05a3942286eca", "question": "In which city does the film \"Home Alone\" take place?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9e1b6e748bb36357acdf6", "question": "Who is the singer behind the albums \"1989\" and \"Reputation\"?", "answer": "Taylor Swift", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febda007e83c707845b2180", "question": "In 2009, which artist set the record for the longest leap to number-one in Billboard Hot 100 history?", "answer": "Kelly Clarkson's 2009 hit \"My Life Would Suck Without You\" jumped from number-97 to number-1 in the course of a week.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b29", "question": "What Hanna-Barbera cartoon character was always causing trouble for Ranger Smith?", "answer": "Yogi Bear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad9f", "question": "During what war was the construction of the Pentagon completed?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934d", "question": "What year did \"The Tonight Show\" first air?", "answer": "1954", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cdd6bb53d1af658864ed", "question": "What year marked the first appearance of Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "1939", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff25a8431a458464a93c472", "question": "Which condiment is traditionally served with fried seafood in the United States?", "answer": "Tartar Sauce", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe908d901dd7bf43be5e888", "question": "What kind of scientist was Linus Pauling?", "answer": "Chemist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f4", "question": "In The Simpsons, what sits next to the basement door in the Simpson's house?", "answer": "Grandfather clock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab85", "question": "Who was the first person to reach the North Pole in 1909?", "answer": "Robert Peary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597742ce284458f1d7854422", "question": "What two Coaches on \"The Voice\" US have been on from season 1 through season 14?", "answer": "Blake Shelton and Adam Levine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b002", "question": "Who was the primary author of the Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bb35bc32627b8fe95581bec", "question": "When Achilles cross-dressed as a woman to avoid the war, what name did he use?", "answer": "Pyrrha", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339189", "question": "What organization do the FLash, Wonder Woman, Superman, Batman and the Green Lantern all belong to?", "answer": "The Justice League of America", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3af", "question": "Which British designer invented the Dual Cyclone bagless vacuum cleaner?", "answer": "James Dyson", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3e", "question": "US President Woodrow Wilson was a member of what political party?", "answer": "Democratic Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff51aafff04d658268c9308", "question": "Who was Telemachus?", "answer": "Telemachus was the only son of Odysseus and Penelope.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a9e930f7ccba3ffe45786c1", "question": "What year did Stella Gibbons publish the novel \"Cold Comfort Farm\"?", "answer": "1932", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c046", "question": "Which world champion was beaten by a machine called Deep Blue in 1997?\u00a0", "answer": "Gary Kasparov", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee0", "question": "Who was king of England at the time of the Gunpowder Plot?", "answer": "King James I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8fb", "question": "What sport features strikers and sweepers?", "answer": "Soccer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa3ce6ce05a3942286eaa", "question": "Which of the Beach Boys actually knew how to surf?", "answer": "Dennis Wilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523c4c736d4be723796b37", "question": "What is the name of the highway that travels through all ten Canadian provinces?", "answer": "Trans-Canada Highway, or Route Transcanadienne", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071f473745b36be73039ea", "question": "What is the name of Dana and Em's father in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Wayne Cypress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ec4d08d98002fdd633ba", "question": "Which character, that first appeared in the book \"Winnie-the-Pooh\", loves watercress?", "answer": "Roo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab51", "question": "Ljubljana is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Slovenia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600cc2f26de0eb824d4052e8", "question": "What South American country is a former Dutch colony?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab15dabaab681b0929217e", "question": "What was the world\u2019s first mass-produced car to feature an all-aluminium body?", "answer": "Honda NSX", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7bf73877e98cb97778968", "question": "Until 1910, what was the capital of Oklahoma?", "answer": "Guthrie", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c90d18552800b05cac20f12", "question": "Monrovia is the capital of what African country?", "answer": "Liberia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8761ec223966ae8f8814", "question": "Jim Morrison was the lead singer of which prominent 1960's rock band?", "answer": "the Doors", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc13f5469bb8041d07a082", "question": "Something that is toward the end or away from the center of the body can also be called what?", "answer": "Distal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339807", "question": "What nationality are the members of the 80's pop band \"A-ha\"?", "answer": "Norwegian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a283", "question": "Queen provided the soundtrack to which 1980 space opera starring Max von Sydow and Brian Blessed?", "answer": "Flash Gordon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c221", "question": "What is the name of Canada's national anthem?", "answer": "O Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba39f874c93a3298b213e", "question": "Who was nicknamed La Pucelle d'Orl\u00e9ans?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea461dff048f679a45ab9e", "question": "What is the Hawaiian name for yellow fin tuna?", "answer": "Ahi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b75", "question": "In \"Napoleon Dynamite\", what type of animal is Napoleon's grandmother's pet, Tina?", "answer": "llama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feddd3a6ce05a3942286da2", "question": "What alias does Andy use to launder the warden's ill-gotten money in the film \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Andy goes by the alias, Randall Stephens, to launder Norton's money.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990aefbb72eedf883a8c703", "question": "In what collection of sports would you use spikes and blocks?", "answer": "Athletics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b789", "question": "What underdog knocked out Mike Tyson in Tokyo in 1990?", "answer": "Buster Douglas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf4", "question": "How many Grammy Awards did Frank Sinatra receive during his career?", "answer": "11", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a20512f2a7826b9b8717", "question": "What 1980's cartoon was a showcase for \"New Wave\" Music videos?", "answer": "Kidd Video", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b32359ebf195a31e15d73b1", "question": "Who were defeated by the New York Mets in the 1969 World Series?", "answer": "The Orioles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8aa2501dd7bf43be5e758", "question": "\"Cohen\" is Hebrew for what?", "answer": "Priest", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133931a", "question": "In the 1967 movie \"Cool Hand Luke\", how many hard-boiled eggs does Lucas eat in one hour?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d85", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Christopher Wallace?", "answer": "The Notorious B.I.G.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067987ff9c0647b50a804f", "question": "In March, 2016, former politician Radovan Karadzic was sentenced to 40 years in prison for genocide and crimes against humanity committed during what war?", "answer": "Bosnian War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d4", "question": "What movie gave us the line \"Nobody puts Baby in a corner!\"?", "answer": "Dirty Dancing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb6e", "question": "Approximately how many plain chocolate Hershey's Kisses are there to a pound of chocolate?", "answer": "Approximately 100", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2115a31a458464a93c441", "question": "Which American author was awarded both the Nobel Prize in Literature and Presidential Medal of Freedom?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac85", "question": "What was banned in Mississippi in 1907 that didn't become legal there again until 1966?", "answer": "Alcohol", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb68675dad637d903c8842", "question": "Which is the southernmost country in the European Union with no Mediterranean coastline?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c7cffbde8045e48466c8", "question": "Masses are to Newton's Gravitational Law as charges are to what?", "answer": "Coulomb's Law", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c79e877e98cb977789d3", "question": "Which state is home to the Valley of Ten Thousand Smokes?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388bc", "question": "What game does the Queen of Hearts order Alice to play?", "answer": "Croquet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b52c", "question": "What postal code has Canada Post assigned to Santa Claus?", "answer": "H0H 0H0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c8", "question": "What is James Dean's middle name?", "answer": "Byron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a1", "question": "What year was inventor Alexander Graham Bell born in?", "answer": "1847", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5907214c3745b36be73039f6", "question": "What is the name of the popular Christmas song that Will\u2019s dad composed in the 2002 film \"About a Boy\"?", "answer": "Santa\u2019s Super Sleigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd41bec223966ae8f88ca", "question": "Some of the musical compositions for \"The Hateful Eight\" are unused scores from what movie?", "answer": "\"The Thing\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029f42cad1ec93f27df75d", "question": "Which empire gave the world the Pilsner?", "answer": "The Austrian Empire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c60e", "question": "What does a herpetologist study?", "answer": "Reptiles and amphibians", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339345", "question": "What real-life family was the inspiration for the TV show \"Partridge Family\"?", "answer": "The Cowsills", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c0", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Kazakhstan and Iran?", "answer": "Turkmenistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5902a166cad1ec93f27df776", "question": "What dialect term describes rough cider made from unselected apples?", "answer": "Scrumpy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7c", "question": "During what war was the novel \"For Whom the Bell Tolls\" set?", "answer": "Spanish Civil War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcea", "question": "What two things need to be combined to form an \"interrobang\"?", "answer": "A question mark and an exclamation point", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062ac3c9d816e292245c1b", "question": "What American artist is known for the Nurse Paintings?", "answer": "The Nurse Paintings are a series by Richard Prince inspired by the covers and titles of pulp romance novels.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ee", "question": "What event occurs at Walthamstow Stadium?", "answer": "Greyhound Racing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f3", "question": "How many fingers does a boy scout extend in a salute?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909cdc8bb53d1af658864ec", "question": "What year marked the first appearance of Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "1939", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63d", "question": "A Calorie is a measurement of what?", "answer": "Energy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c889", "question": "What is the chemical name for a dentist's \"laughing gas\"?", "answer": "Nitrous oxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3818ff048f679a45ab21", "question": "What is a unit that measures force?", "answer": "Newtons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29e", "question": "Who was the male lead in the 1955 film \"To Catch a Thief\"?", "answer": "Cary Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ff", "question": "Although it's referred to as a \"sea\", what body of water is actually the largest lake in the world?", "answer": "Caspian Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c86a", "question": "What is the more common name for benzoic sulfinide?", "answer": "Saccharin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909d2f6bb53d1af6588650e", "question": "Who played the lead role in the 1983 film \"Merry Christmas, Mr. Lawrence\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6571aae7e414034b5aed6", "question": "Samuel Tilden, Grover Cleveland, Al Gore, and Hillary Clinton share what distinction among U.S. presidential candidates?", "answer": "They won the popular vote but lost the electoral college vote", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a610", "question": "What is the world\u2019s most southerly capital city?", "answer": "Wellington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339253", "question": "What rocker's song \"Rock Is Dead\" is heard in the movie \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Marilyn Manson's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b5", "question": "What did A.J. stand for on the TV show \"Simon & Simon\"?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4dd0206d333868d34d6fe", "question": "What documents were responsible for establishing the 17th Parallel as the line that separated Vietnam during the Vietnam War?", "answer": "Geneva Accords", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339031", "question": "Jim Rhodes is the alter ego of which Marvel comic book hero?", "answer": "War Machine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c9e", "question": "What Ray Charles song was the basis for Kanye West's \"Gold Digger\"?", "answer": "I Got a Woman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c88e83422f44c2d77a29c46", "question": "Reaching 20,320 feet (6,194 meters) above sea level, Denali is located in what US state?", "answer": " Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6f", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Missouri?", "answer": "Jefferson City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b891", "question": "The Tour de France was first staged in which decade?", "answer": "1900s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f3", "question": "What type of food is Lollo Rosso?", "answer": "Lettuce", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339225", "question": "Who plays the role of Craig the puppeteer's wife in \"Being John Malkovich\"?", "answer": "Cameron Diaz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af1", "question": "What sporting competition was the focus of the 2007 film \"Balls of Fury\"?", "answer": "Ping Pong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b344", "question": "Which US President was known as \"the peanut president\"?", "answer": "Jimmy Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69b7220565ad31a57c75f", "question": "What English code breaker created a machine that helped to decrypt Nazi messages?", "answer": "Alan Turing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c550fbde8045e48466ab", "question": "Which ocean mammal is nicknamed the killer whale?", "answer": "Orca -- Orcas are called killer whales due to their aggression while hunting prey.  However, orcas are large dolphins, not whales.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c176", "question": "What type of instrument is a Celesta?", "answer": "Keyboard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d5", "question": "If it is 1:00 a.m. in Alaska, what would the time be in New York?", "answer": "5:00 a.m.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da3", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Tulliver?", "answer": "George Eliot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a001", "question": "What British TV series featured Tinky Winky, Dipsy, Laa-Laa, and Po?", "answer": "Teletubbies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea467dff048f679a45aba3", "question": "What happens to your skin's blood vessels as you exercise?", "answer": "They widen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e72cce8d0874f1a5e2d1c25", "question": "What is a \"Winkle Picker\" or \"Winklepicker\"?", "answer": "An English long pointed shoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba9d", "question": "How much wider is a tennis court during a doubles match than a singles match?", "answer": "9 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec88e0ec223966ae8f8824", "question": "In 2011, which music superstar launched her own social media website?", "answer": "In 2011 Lady Gaga launched her \"Little Monsters\" social media network", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f3e001dd7bf43be5e819", "question": "POTUS stands for what?", "answer": "President Of The United States", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b042", "question": "What English king was known as the \"Lionheart\"?", "answer": "Richard (I)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f1", "question": "What was compiled and published for the first time, in New York, in 1936?", "answer": "Pop music chart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb611a5dad637d903c882d", "question": "What is the Golden Gate Bridge named after?", "answer": "Golden Gate was named after the narrow, 300-foot-deep Golden Gate Strait which flows underneath it.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339741", "question": "Peter Marshall was the host of what game show for 15 years?", "answer": "The Hollywood Squares", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c6", "question": "What is the thin layer of foam appearing on top of an espresso called?", "answer": "Crema", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba2d6874c93a3298b2135", "question": "Which Italian won the 1998 Tour de France bicycle race?", "answer": "Marco Pantani", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b44b", "question": "On August 2, 1876, Jack McCall gunned down which famous lawman?", "answer": "Wild Bill Hickok", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ae9503574a5ce6b56b824f", "question": "Lilongwe is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c033", "question": "What is the more common name for serigraphy?", "answer": "Screen printing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfdff2db668d7dfe168b5b5", "question": "Which duo is credited with inventing the \"Spinning Frame\"?", "answer": "Richard Arkwright and John Kay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339542", "question": "What kind of dog is Ren on \"The Ren and Stimpy Show\"?", "answer": "Chihuahua", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be21", "question": "George Fox is traditionally called the founder of what religious group?", "answer": "The Quakers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7fa", "question": "What are the only two South American countries that do not border Brazil?", "answer": "Chile and Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec83ccec223966ae8f87f9", "question": "The late Michael Jackson is widely known as the \"King of Pop\". But who is considered the \"Queen of Pop\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a942", "question": "At what Seward Peninsula city does the Iditarod end?", "answer": "Nome, Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3f", "question": "In what key is Johann Pachelbel's famous \"Canon\"?", "answer": "D", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5da856c01aec824685d88d07", "question": "Who was the Texan city of Austin named after?", "answer": "Stephen F. Austin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f1", "question": "What happens when you roll three consecutive doubles in a game of Monopoly?", "answer": "You go to jail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339486", "question": "In what US city does Hitchcock's movie \"Vertigo\" take place?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded1beea2747c8aff16d36", "question": "What year gave birth to the word \"motel\"?", "answer": "1925", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f4", "question": "What year did Volkswagen introduce the Golf GTI model?", "answer": "1976", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133889f", "question": "What Vladimir Nabakov novel features Professor Humbert in love with a 12 year old girl?", "answer": "Lolita", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd8", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"I\"?", "answer": "India", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c9f811b4e2c7fbd389674f", "question": "What country does Cafe au lait originate from?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339774", "question": "Which company created the Oscar-winning film Finding Nemo?", "answer": "Pixar Animation Studios", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afaf", "question": "In 1907, what did the volunteer force \"The Yeomanry\" become known as?", "answer": "British Territorial Army", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a007", "question": "What city's music scene gave us R.E.M., Danger Mouse, and the B-52s?", "answer": "Athens, Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926e", "question": "How tall is the Academy Award statue?", "answer": "13.5 inches", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b7c", "question": "What did the letters in the name of the cable network HBO originally stand for?", "answer": "Home Box Office", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d0d", "question": "Uriah Heep was a character in what Charles Dickens novel?", "answer": "David Copperfield", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a0", "question": "What movie starred Johnny Depp as Willy Wonka?", "answer": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339acc", "question": "What type of birds are the stars of the 2006 animated film \"Happy Feet\"?", "answer": "Penguins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f1676af7c52aae91cc07b9", "question": "The Republic of Guinea-Bissau is located on which African coast?", "answer": "Western coast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b97", "question": "Whose movie debut was opposite Humphrey Bogart in 1944's \"To Have and Have Not\"?", "answer": "Lauren Bacall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901db26709c1c34536e6eb1", "question": "In what sport would a contestant perform a \"Fosberry Flop\"?", "answer": "High jump", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c870", "question": "What is a Chinese gooseberry?", "answer": "A kiwifruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc38eec223966ae8f887f", "question": "Who won the 1981 Grammy for \"Record of the Year\"?", "answer": "Christopher Cross for \"Sailing\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede45f6ce05a3942286ddd", "question": "Who penned the classic songs \"Bad Moon Rising\", \"Who'll Stop The Rain\", and \"Lodi\"?", "answer": "John Fogarty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de2", "question": "What \"Desperate Housewives\" creator broke into TV as a personal assistant to actress Dixie Carter?", "answer": "Marc Cherry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e0", "question": "What term is given to the scientific study of all aspects of the life of fungi?", "answer": "Mycology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e3", "question": "Which TV series was set in Walnut Grove, Minnesota?", "answer": "Little House on the Prairie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523fff736d4be723796b5d", "question": "Which city became the first capital of the Province of Canada in 1841?", "answer": "Kingston, Ontario", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b840", "question": "In which sport would you be judged on your pike or your jack knife?", "answer": "Diving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b661", "question": "In baseball, a \"gopher pitch\" is referred to as what?", "answer": "A pitch hit for a home run", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff66f0652a821ff76ae8b1c", "question": "In Iowa, it\u2019s a misdemeanor to mislabel margarine as what?", "answer": "Butter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390cc", "question": "What type of instrument is a Celesta?", "answer": "Keyboard", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd81fc7d0de9af39e9d4699", "question": "What virtue do the red stripes on the American flag stand for?", "answer": "Valor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b19", "question": "What is the first book of the New Testament?", "answer": "The Gospel According to St. Matthew", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c135", "question": "Which significant beverage did John Pemberton invent in 1886?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af3e", "question": "What was Franklin D. Roosevelt's middle name?", "answer": "Delano", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133951b", "question": "Who voiced Hercules in the 1997 Disney movie with the same name?", "answer": "Tate Donovan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010ca1f0775fa611bce67f3", "question": "What Apple computer was named after Steve Jobs' daughter?", "answer": "Lisa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339775", "question": "What movie contains the line, \"Sorry, we would have come earlier but your husband wasn't dead yet\"?", "answer": "Naked Gun", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339497", "question": "How many children do Daniel and Miranda have in the movie \"Mrs. Doubtfire\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf8", "question": "Who wrote \"Uncle Tom's Cabin\"?", "answer": "Harriet Beecher Stowe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aced", "question": "Who was Jimmy Carter's vice president?", "answer": "Walter (Fritz) Mondale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e3f3965cb9e8bda6821364", "question": "When was the Rosetta Stone found?", "answer": "1799", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c98f0775fa611bce67ec", "question": "What is the decorative strip along the top of a wall called?", "answer": "Molding -- It comes from Classical architecture, where they were designed to give a building character and hide its imperfections.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd7367e83c707845b2172", "question": "Which NFL team's name was inspired by a famous writer?", "answer": "Baltimore Ravens (The name comes from the poem \"The Raven,\" written by Edgar Allan Poe who called Baltimore home.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a031", "question": "Which former Golden Girl reads an audio version of one of Peter's erotic novels in \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Betty White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a992661d1b4d384d5d697", "question": "What year did the TV show \"Gunsmoke\" change its length from 30 minutes to 1 hour?", "answer": "1961", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc03c6de0eb824d4052d8", "question": "How did the Pacific Ocean get its name?", "answer": "Portuguese explorer, Ferdinand Magellan named it \"Mar Pacifico\", which means \"peaceful sea\" in both Portuguese and Spanish.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60136faa1381754895396379", "question": "In 2000, what character was elected U.S. President in the DC universe?", "answer": "Lex Luthor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b3", "question": "In what ship's 1945 sinking were there as many as eighty sailors eaten by whitetip sharks?", "answer": "The USS Indianapolis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b979", "question": "What was the fabled city of gold that some 16th century Europeans believed existed in South America?", "answer": "El Dorado", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909cb53bb53d1af658864d7", "question": "In the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", how many drummers are drumming?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a838", "question": "What Ivy League university is located in Ithaca, NY?", "answer": "Cornell", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cb70cd5f96e155acab35d2f", "question": "What country once technically fought a war against a species of bird?", "answer": "Australia, \"The Emu War\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d3", "question": "What New York Yankee was nickname the \"Iron Horse\"?", "answer": "Lou Gehrig", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2594031a458464a93c46b", "question": "How many years are in a \"score\"?", "answer": "Twenty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339977", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Lenny has a master's degree in what field?", "answer": "Nuclear Physics", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad7", "question": "What novel begins with the words \"Marley was dead...\"?", "answer": "A Christmas Carol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339936", "question": "Who played Willie Scott in the movie \"Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom\"?", "answer": "Kate Capshaw", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049ca0cf93664eb10486a8", "question": "Which famous rapper died on Friday, September 13, 1996?", "answer": "Tupac Shakur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c023", "question": "In what city was fashion designer Gianni Versace killed?", "answer": "Miami Beach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7bfe0877e98cb9777896b", "question": "What country borders the Caspian Sea, Persian Gulf, and Gulf of Oman?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab1071baab681b0929216b", "question": "Mad Shelia is a Chinese action movie that's heavily influenced by which George Miller-directed blockbuster from 2015?", "answer": "Mad Max: Fury Road", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338961", "question": "What musical instrument is Antonio Stradivari most famous for making?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "591c353e815febcc896f925a", "question": "Jakarta is located on which Indonesian island?", "answer": "Java", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc10d6ce05a3942286f0d", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Private Eyes\"?", "answer": "Hall and Oates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a9", "question": "What year was author J. D. Salinger born?", "answer": "1919", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c74", "question": "Rupert Giles was the librarian-mentor on what popular TV show?", "answer": "Buffy the Vampire Slayer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b906364247bf200fb886", "question": "Aulophobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Flutes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3234fbbf195a31e15d73aa", "question": "Which artist starred in the title role of the film \"Merry Christmas, Mr. Lawrence\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfbedf003d27d341092bd2", "question": "Where is the world's largest tropical orchid garden?", "answer": "Singapore", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f3ca01dd7bf43be5e817", "question": "HIPAA stands for what in the US?", "answer": "Health Insurance Portability Accountability Act", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35a", "question": "Who found the long lost explorer David Livingston?", "answer": "Henry Morton Stanley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af25d1bb63e5727cf5a4862", "question": "Michael Jackson's video for \"Black or White\" featured which famous child actor?", "answer": "Macaulay Culkin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c30d", "question": "What flowers are known as \"mums\"?", "answer": "Chrysanthemums", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9e6", "question": "On what sea is the Crimea?", "answer": "Black Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5989a867cb8751d53e7d75fa", "question": "United States' observation of Mardi Gras was started in which city and state?", "answer": "Mobile, Alabama", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a6", "question": "What European nation still pledges its allegiance to a foreign monarch in its national anthem?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf9", "question": "In 1985, what type of creature did Ringling Brothers Barnum & Bailey Circus claim to have found?", "answer": "A unicorn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b27c", "question": "Who used hypnotism to treat the hemophilia of Tsarevich Alexei?", "answer": "Rasputin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff510e2d24dd593ee3eacc7", "question": "What military campaign is colloquially known as the \"Bekaa Valley Turkey Shoot\"?", "answer": "Code-named\u00a0Operation Mole Cricket 19, Israeli aircraft destroyed 82-86 of 100 Syrian aircraft in the 1982 Lebanon War.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe738b8eec85e375820b266", "question": "Which African country was formerly known as Abyssinia?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c7d", "question": "Who is the creator of the \"Desperate Housewives\" TV series?", "answer": "Marc Cherry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c825", "question": "What common aquarium fish is named for the naturalist who discovered it in Trinidad in 1876?", "answer": "The guppy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff20ed931a458464a93c42b", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Parallel Lines\"?", "answer": "Blondie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0cc", "question": "What are the names of the twins on the TV show \"Thundercats\"?", "answer": "WilyKit and WilyKat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af14", "question": "What caused the Tacoma Narrows Bridge to collapse in 1940?", "answer": "Wind (poor design and engineering led to this)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a70e", "question": "What city in Ohio is known as the \"rubber capital of the US\"?", "answer": "Akron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071f1e3745b36be73039e8", "question": "What is the full name of Em Cypress, Dana's sister and reviver, in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Martha Ann Cypress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339303", "question": "In the 2004 movie \"Anchorman: The Legend of Ron Burgundy\", what musical instrument does Ron play?", "answer": "The jazz flute", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cdc", "question": "What sci-fi movie featured Michael Rennie and Patricia Neal?", "answer": "The Day the Earth Stood Still", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc0246de0eb824d4052d7", "question": "What city is known as the \"polar bear capital of the world\"?", "answer": "Churchill, Manitoba -- It's fairly common to see one strolling through the Canadian town or outside one's bedroom window at night.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71c", "question": "In what country does Santa typically sport a long coat and beard?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa58973838c5c8a417f26", "question": "What insects are sometimes called devil\u2019s darning needles?", "answer": "Dragonfly (They\u2019ve also been called darners and devil\u2019s arrows.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339513", "question": "What actor voiced Mushu in the movie \"Mulan\"?", "answer": "Eddie Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c6c1fbde8045e48466b9", "question": "Which naturally occurring element is heaviest by atomic weight?", "answer": "Uranium -- At present, ununoctium is the heaviest but it's man-made, and so disqualified as a \"naturally\" occurring element.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff6719552a821ff76ae8b24", "question": "What manufacturer introduced \"Pringles\" potato chips in 1967?", "answer": "Procter & Gamble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e4", "question": "Whose memory is the movie \"Gladiator\" dedicated to?", "answer": "Oliver Reed's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b685", "question": "What insulates the ice cream to prevent it from melting in the hot dish \"Baked Alaska\"?", "answer": "Meringue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e5", "question": "The Khyber pass joins which\u00a0two countries?", "answer": "Afghanistan and Pakistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b145", "question": "What was the name for the German mercenaries who fought against the American rebels during the Revolutionary War?", "answer": "Hessians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b85ae662d71a53651022", "question": "Petroglyph is an engraving or image created on what?", "answer": "Stone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45f", "question": "Who received a patent for the first electric razor in 1930?", "answer": "Jacob Schick", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cb7e877e98cb97778a1c", "question": "Which country's Easter brunch typically includes a ryemeal soup known as zurek?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f9f42a8af848b908361b86f", "question": "Who was the first full-term President of Sierra Leone?", "answer": "Siaka Stevens", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a7", "question": "In what film did Steve Martin play the character Navin Johnson?", "answer": "The Jerk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecccbdec223966ae8f88a4", "question": "In what movie did Benedict Cumberbatch wear dentures that were an exact replica of Alan Turing's 60-year old set of false teeth?", "answer": "\"The Imitation Game\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5a0", "question": "How many tusks sprout from the snout of an adult male warthog?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e8", "question": "Who was Tommy Lee Jones' upperclassman roommate at Harvard?", "answer": "Al Gore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad43", "question": "Which country seized the USS Pueblo after accusing its American crew of unlawful spying in 1968?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd3", "question": "What instrument did jazz bandleader Count Basie play?", "answer": "Piano", "category": "entertainment"}]